https://slama.dev/comeback/
https://slama.dev/comeback/
Deserts.
Pouště.
Arid wastelands without a drop of moisture cover over 10% of the Earth's land surface.
Vyprahlé pustiny bez kapky vláhy pokrývají přes 10 % povrchu zemské pevniny.
The beauty of the desert is alluring at first glance, but if you enter this kingdom of eternal drought, a battle with burning thirst awaits you, and for the weak, even death.
Krása pouště na první pohled láká, ale vstoupíte-li do tohoto království věčného sucha, čeká vás boj s palčivou žízní a na slabé jedince i smrt.
So what?
No co?
Every thirst needs a reason.
Každá žízeň potřebuje důvod.
It can not only survive in this furnace, but even thrive.
Dokáže v této výhni nejen přežít, ale i prospívat.
Hey, bro?
Jo, brácha?
Yeah?
No?
Have you talked to the building manager lately?
Nemluvil jsi teď někdy se správcovou?
No.
Ne.
Great.
Bezva.
The Bedouins liken me to a coffee plant.
Beduíni mě přirovnávají ke kahávatu.
A gift from God, perhaps for its versatile use.
Dar boží, snad pro jeho všestranné použití.
The Bactrian camel can survive without drinking for up to two months.
Velbloud dvouhrbý dokáže vydržet bez napití až dva měsíce.
Incredible.
Neuvěřitelný.
Yeah, you didn't even go near her.
Jo, ani ses k ní nepřiblížil.
What?
Co?
No, since you told me not to.
Ne, když jsi mi to zakázal.
Great.
Bezva.
I'm writing a request for a new water heater.
Píšu teď žádost o novej bojler.
I hope she's forgotten you're my brother by now.
Tak doufám, že už zapomněla, že jsi můj bratr.
It excels at spitting.
Vyniká v plivání.
It can spit over great distances with surprising accuracy.
Doplivne na velkou vzdálenost s překvapivou přesností.
If only I could spit like that.
Takhle umět fluskat.
I wouldn't have missed the building manager from that window yesterday.
To bych správcovou včera z toho okna neminul.
Not only does it spit saliva, but also partially digested stomach contents.
Nejen že plivne jen sliny, ale i natrávený obsah žaludku.
I got her all the way from the mezzanine.
Dostal jsem jí až z mezipatra.
Which camel herders try to train out of them in the desert.
Čemuž se velbloudáři snaží odnaučit pouští.
Of course, in vain.
Samozřejmě marně.
Dad, I'm off.
Tati, tak já jdu.
And please don't forget to turn off the chicken.
Hlavně prosím tě nezapomeň vypnout kuře.
Where is it?
Kde je?
When it's done.
No až bude hotový.
And how will I know?
A jak to poznám?
God, you poke it with a fork.
Ježiš, píchneš do něj vidličkou.
And?
A?
What do you mean "and"?
Co a?
What happens when I poke it with a fork?
Co bude, až do něj píchnu vidličkou?
You'll know it's done.
No poznáš, že je hotový.
Okay.
Aha.
What?
Co?
Nothing.
Nic.
You were huffing.
Funěl jsi.
I just sighed.
Jen jsem si povzdechl.
It's healthy, I enjoy it, and I'm good at it.
Je to zdravý, dělám to ráda a jde mi to.
But you're practically naked doing it.
Ale jsi u toho skoro nahá.
In belly dancing you have to show the belly, that's obvious, isn't it?
Při břišních tancích musí být vidět břicho, to je snad jasný, ne?
She's too young to be writhing around half-naked somewhere.
Na to, aby se zkroutila někde polonahá, na to jsi ještě mladá.
Marcel, you said she was too old for it.
Marceli, ty jsi říkal, že je na to moc stará.
That's not what I said.
Takhle jsem to neřekl.
You said at her age she should maintain her dignity.
Řekl jsi, že by ve svým věku měla dbát na důstojnost.
I meant well.
Myslel jsem to dobře.
Iva, Iva, I tried, but I just can't keep the diamond in my belly button.
Ivo, Ivo, zkoušela jsem to, ale já ten diamant v pupíku prostě neudržím.
Where did you get a diamond?
Kde jsi vzala diamant?
Well, I tried first with a chestnut and then a ladybug, nothing held.
No, zkoušela jsem to nejdřív s kaštenem a potom s beruškou, nedrželo nic.
The bayaderes have the diamonds glued on.
Bajadéry tam mají ty diamanty přilepeny.
Really?
Fakt?
She'd never do that to a ladybug.
To by berušce nikdy neudělala.
Ladies, I don't want to come across as some old fuddy-duddy, but there are so many lovely Czech national dances.
Děvčata, já tady tedy nechci vypadat jako nějaký staromilec, ale je přece tolik pěkných českých národních tanců.
Like what?
Jako třeba?
Like the Czech Beseda.
Jako třeba česká beseda.
Ladies and gentlemen, the Beseda begins, ladies and gentlemen, the Beseda is on.
Páni dámy, beseda začíná, páni dámy, beseda je.
We've got the folk costume.
Kroj máme.
You watch the chicken.
Ty hlídej kuře.
Great!
Super!
You're connected to the water heater in the neighboring building.
Jsi připojená na bojler v sousedním baráku.
Through a condensation pipe.
Kondenzní trubkou.
And Pacovsky?
A Pacovský?
Thanks.
Dík.
And they won't notice.
A nepoznaj to tam.
At home or here?
Doma alebo tu?
Here. They're cops, after all.
Tu. Veď sú to policajti.
They're dumber than Pacovsky.
Ty sú blbší jako Pacovský.
Alright then.
Tak fajn.
Tomas.
Tomáš.
What could he want?
Co může chtít?
Yeah.
No.
You poke it with a fork.
Píchneš do ní vidličkou.
So you know if the meat comes off the bone.
Abys věděla, jestli jde maso od kosti.
Bye then.
Tak čau.
Easy.
Poho.
So, how did it go?
Tak, jak to šlo?
Great.
Skvělý.
We're going to dance for charity.
Budeme tancovat pro charitu.
In front of people?
To jako před lidma?
Dad.
Tati.
But you promised you wouldn't do it in public.
Vždyť jsi slíbila, že to nebudeš dělat na veřejnosti.
No, I said I wouldn't let any strangers into the studio.
Ne, říkala jsem, že do toho studia nikoho cizího nepustím.
Yeah?
No?
And that's true.
No a je to pravda.
Like, they've thrown Lexa out three times already, camera and all.
Třeba Lexu tam teď vyhodili už třikrát, i s foťákem.
Good for them.
Dobře udělali.
What kind of event is it?
Co to je za akci?
A charity evening supporting women from developing countries.
Dobročinný večer na podporu žen z rozvojových zemí.
The proceeds will go to the Show Your Face campaign so they don't have to wear burqas.
Výtěžek půjde na kampaň Ukaž svou tvář, aby nemusely nosit burku.
It'll be at the Hilton.
Bude to v Hiltonu.
And maybe even the Qatari ambassador will come.
A možná přijede i katarský velvyslanec.
I've got no problem with showing faces, but the fact that you'll be showing everything else to some Arab, that I just don't like.
S ukazováním tváře problém nemám, ale to, že budeš před nějakým Arabem ukazovat ještě všechno ostatní, tak to se mi prostě nelíbí.
Sometimes I wonder if you're the Arab here.
Někdy si říkám, jestli nejsi Arab ty.
What?
Co?
What about the chicken?
Co kuře?
It's fine, I let it finish.
V pořádku, nechal jsem ho dojít.
What?
Co?
Finish.
Dojít.
Thing is, I don't want to leave it in the storage room, Ozzak keeps picking at it.
Jakože nechci ho nechávat v kumbálu, Ozzák mi to pořád otrhává.
He probably thinks it's beer money.
Asi si myslí, že to jsou drobný na pivo.
Good day, Marcelka.
Dobrý den, Marcelko.
Hello.
Dobrý.
I had ten missed calls from you on my phone, did something happen?
Měla jsem od vás v mobilu deset nepřijatých hovorů, stalo se něco?
No, everything's fine.
To ne, v pořádku, všechno.
So I can delete the text about how to tell when meat comes off the bone.
Takže tu SMSku, jak se pozná, že jde maso od kosti, si smažu.
Ivuska, did you tell your dad the big news?
Ivuško, řekla jsi tatínkovi tu velkou novinu?
Yeah.
Jo.
And is preparing a performance for an important charity event in front of high society dignified enough?
A přípravu vystoupení na významné charitativní akci před společenskou smetánkou dost důstojné?
Well, we wouldn't be dancing in burqas.
No, nebychom tancovaly v burkách.
Now, Iva, don't make me out to be some fuddy-duddy.
Tak, Ivo, nedělej tady ze mě nějakého staromilce.
Well, I'm off.
No, tak já letím.
I can't wait to take a shower.
Už se nemůžu dočkat, až se osprchuju.
Me too.
Já taky.
Hold on, today it's my turn.
No moment, dneska jsem na řadě já.
But I've been sweating for an hour and you've been sitting by the oven watching your chicken.
Jenomže já se teďka hodinu potila a ty jsi seděl u trouby a sledoval svý kuře.
Ugh, risotto.
Fuj, risotto.
If Dad hadn't stripped all the meat off the bone, you could've had chicken.
Kdyby táta neoškubal všechno maso od kosti, mohl jsi mít kuře.
Just eat.
Jen jezte.
Risotto is a good and economical meal.
Risotto je dobré a úsporné jídlo.
And it'll last until tomorrow.
A navíc vydrží do zítřka.
We have to cut back because of you anyway.
Stejně se kvůli tobě musíme uskrovnit.
So you're buying me one?
Takže ty mě okoupíš?
Eat more.
Přidej.
What are you buying him?
Co mu koupíš?
Van Gouda.
Van Gouda.
Dad.
Tati.
No.
Ne.
But you promised!
Vždyť jsi to ten slíbil!
I said we'll buy a water heater because the co-op won't pay for one thanks to you.
Řekl jsem, že se koupí bojler, protože ho družstvo kvůli tobě nezaplatí.
And this taking-turns showering is awful.
A to sprchování na střídačku je hrozný.
They rejected the request?
Zamítli tu žádost?
No, but I found it crumpled up by the dumpsters.
Ne, ale našel jsem ji zmačkanou u popelnic.
That looks rejected.
To vypadá zamítnutě.
I'm not going to eat scraps for something I don't even use.
Nebudu žrát zrní kvůli něčemu, co nepoužívám.
Oh please, yesterday you used up all the hot water.
Ale prosím tě, včera jsi vyplýtval všechnu teplou vodu.
Me?
Já?
Excuse me!
No dovol!
You went into the bathroom, the shower was running.
Šel jsi do koupelny, aby byla slyšet sprcha.
I was making the sound with my mouth!
To jsem dělal pusou!
And you still managed to sing Cossack songs at the same time.
A přitom jsi ještě zvládnul zpívat kozačky.
Look, I won't stand for this kind of insult.
Hele, já si tady nenechám urážet.
First they reject my camel and then they accuse me of bathing.
Nejdřív se mi zamítne velbloud a potom mě obviněj, že se meju.
You can't just walk around in a mess.
To nemůžeš chodit ve zmaru.
It's closer from here.
Tady to mám blíž.
Look, I've got hot water now.
Hele, už mi teče teplá voda.
Do they have beer on tap here?
A teče ti tu pivo?
You're in a great mood.
Ty máš teda náladu.
I've had enough.
Už toho mám dost.
Nobody listens to me.
Nikdo mě neposlouchá.
We're deciding between buying drums or a shoe rack.
Rozhoduje se, jestli se koupí bicí nebo botník.
The shoe rack wins.
Vyhraje botník.
The diapers finally go on sale and what wins?
Konečně zlevněj pípí a co myslíš, že vyhraje?
A rug.
Koberec.
And they vetoed my camel too.
A velblouda mi taky zatrhli.
What would you do with a camel?
Na co by ti byl velbloud?
It's incredibly versatile.
Je ohromně všestranej.
And beautiful.
A krásnej.
We're talking about this two-humped horse.
Mluvíme o takovýmto dvouhrbým koni.
Yeah, also the one-humped kind, that's called a dromedary.
Jo, taky jednohrbej, tomu se říká dromedár.
What would you do with it?
Co bys si s ním dělal?
It'd wait for me outside the pub and take me home.
Čekal by na mě před hospodou a vozil by mě domů.
And if the building manager ambushed me at night, it'd spit right in her face.
A kdyby si na mě v noci počíhala správcová, flusnul by jí do ksichtu.
It really is versatile.
Je fakt všestranej.
Definitely more than a water heater.
Rozhodně víc než bojler.
What water heater?
Jaký bojler?
The one they're buying instead of the spitter.
No ten, co se kupuje místo fluskáka.
Why a water heater?
Na co bojler?
Yours is perfectly fine.
Ten váš je přece v pohodě.
Herko, what's everyone's problem, it's not like I bathe.
Herko, co s tím pořád všichni máte, co pak já se meju?
No, you don't.
No ne, ty ne.
You're a tough guy after all.
Ty jsi přece drsnej chlap.
Exactly.
No proto.
I just wonder if you've heard anything, maybe second-hand.
Já jen jestli o tom nevíš něco třeba z doslechu.
Apparently it gives very little hot water.
Prý dává hrozně málo teplý vody.
When a buddy of mine was filling the tub at our place, there was so little hot water his toy boats were scraping the bottom.
Když si tuhle jeden můj kámoš u nás napouštěl vanu, bylo teplý tak málo, že mu lodičky drhly kýlem o dno.
My buddy is a sailor.
Kámoš je námořník.
Sure.
Jasně.
Is my brother home?
Je brácha doma?
I don't care.
Mně je to jedno.
I'll be right back.
Hned jsem zpátky.
Hey.
Čau.
Hi there.
Ahojce.
Nothing, just passing by.
Nic, jdu jen okolo.
You're passing by?
Jdeš okolo?
In your underwear?
V dětským základu spodě?
I just felt like having a coffee.
Jsem si řekla, že si dám bené.
Want a coffee?
Dáš si kafe?
No.
Ne.
I hear you're buying a water heater.
Prý budeš kupovat bojler.
Yeah, I have to.
No, musím.
Ours is on its last legs.
Ten náš už stojí za pendrek.
What kind are you getting?
A jaký budeš brát?
Well, I was thinking this one.
No, já jsem si říkal, že tenhle.
Small.
Malej.
How small?
Jak malej?
It says right here it's optimal for a family of three.
Vždyť tady píšou, že je optimální pro tříčlennou rodinu.
You'd need one twice as big.
To bys potřeboval dvakrát větší.
Why?
Jak to?
Just to be safe.
Pro jistotu.
What if someone came to visit.
Co kdyby třeba někdo přijel na návštěvu.
But nobody ever visits us.
Ale k nám nikdo nejezdí.
Still.
No, ale stejně.
They lie terribly in those brochures.
Oni v těch prospektech strašně lžou.
They deliberately tell you to buy a smaller one than you need.
Schválně ti píšou, abys koupil menší, než potřebuješ.
And why would they do that?
A proč by to dělali?
The smaller one is cheaper.
Menší je levnější.
Exactly.
No právě.
So wouldn't I expect them to want me to buy the bigger one, since it costs more?
Tak se nebych čekal, že budou chtít, abych si koupil větší, protože je dražší, ne?
See how you fell for it?
Vidíš, jak jsi mi na to skočil?
You buy the small one, it's not enough, and then you buy the big one.
Koupíš malej, nestačí ti, a pak koupíš velkej.
Right.
No.
Get it?
Chápeš to?
They sell two.
Prodaj dva.
Those crooks.
Lumpizlodějský.
I'm glad you understand.
To jsem ráda, že jsi to pochopil.
So the big one.
Takže velkej.
Who's going to install it?
Kdo ti to namontuje?
I don't know, probably some company.
Nevím, asi nějaká firma.
Why not Horvy?
Proč ne Horvy?
I don't know.
Já nevím.
He knows water heaters like nobody else.
Bojlerech se vyzná jako nikdo jinej.
I doubt it, it started acting up ever since you brought him in to tune it up.
No to pochybuju, začalo to blbnout od tý doby, co jsi ho přivedla, aby to pošteloval.
He clearly said that water heater was on its last legs.
Jasně říkal, že ten bojler už to má skoro za sebou.
And he tore up the whole bathroom because of it.
Vždyť tam kvůli tomu rozkopal celou koupelnu.
I bet without his special condensation pipe you wouldn't even be able to shave.
Vsaď se, že bez tý jeho speciální kondenzní trubky už by ses ani neholil.
Well, I'll probably look for someone else.
No a já se asi poohlídnu po někom jiným.
I'll tell Horvy to give you a good price.
Řeknu Horvymu, ať ti udělá cenu.
I'm off then!
Tak já letím!
Wait, you said you'd have a coffee.
Počkej, vždyť jsi říkala, že si dáš bené.
It doesn't take me long.
Mně stačí málo.
I saw you in the shop window, Mambo, the whole time.
Viděl jsem vás ve výloze, Mambo, celou dobu.
Yeah.
No.
I have an important performance coming up, so I devote every free moment to training.
Mám před sebou důležité vystoupení, takže každou volnou chvilku věnuji tréninku.
What did you say?
Říkal jste co?
You couldn't handle proper music.
Na pořádnou muziku byste to nezvládla.
You'll only break your hat, poor fellow.
Přelomíte akorát tak si čepici, chudáku.
Anyone can wiggle their belly.
Kroutit břichy dokáže každej.
I'd advise you not to try it.
Mýt vám, abyste to radši nezkoušela.
Why?
Proč?
You've got so much alcohol in your blood, God knows what would happen if you shook that belly of yours.
Máte v krvi tolik alkoholu, že bůhví, co by se stalo, kdybyste tím pupkem zatřás.
I feel great.
Mám jak z praku.
Ozzak.
Ozzáku.
Got a tenner?
Máš desítku?
Does this look like a kindergarten to you?
Vypadá to tady snad jako školka?
Come on!
Dělej!
Hey, how much could a camel cost?
Hele, na kolik může přijít takovej velbloud?
No idea.
Já nevím.
Horvat said the butcher pays him a liter per hundred kilos for a pig.
Horvát říkal, že za prase dostává od řezníka litr za metrák.
So for a camel it might be similar.
Tak u velblouda to může být podobný.
One tenner.
Jedna desítka.
That's not enough.
To je málo.
Hang on.
Moment.
It works!
Funguje to!
You slipped me a ten and you'll keep charging my brother twelve.
Podstrčila jsi desítku a bráchovi mi budeš furt účtovat dvanáctku.
You want me to cheat my own friend?
Ty chceš po mně, abych okrádala svýho kamaráda?
We'll split it.
Šábnem se.
Deal.
Tak jo.
Yes, right.
Ano, tak.
I wanted to ask if a condensation pipe can be mounted on this model.
Já jsem se chtěl ještě zeptat, jestli na tenhle model jde přimontovat kondenzní trubka.
A condensation pipe.
No kondenzní trubka.
Well, you should know better what it is, right?
No tak to musíte vědět líp, co to je, ne?
One moment.
Moment.
Ivuska, go get the door, I'm on the phone.
Ivuško, běž otevřít, telefonuju.
Okay, I'm back.
No tak už jsem zase tady.
One moment.
Moment.
Go open the door, what if someone's there?
Tak běž otevřít, co když tam někdo bude?
There will be, Marcela is bringing costumes.
Bude, Marcela, přinesí kostýmy.
What if someone else is there?
No a co když tam bude někdo jiný?
So what?
Tak co?
One more moment.
Ještě moment.
They'll see you.
No tak tě uvidí.
Okay, I'm back.
No tak už jsem zase tady.
So, shall we agree?
Tak jak se domluvíme?
For tomorrow?
Na zítřek?
At five?
V pět?
Good, I'm looking forward to it.
Dobře, budu se těšit.
Alright, just for today.
Tak jo, dneska jenom.
Who's here?
Kdo tu je?
Nobody else.
Nikdo jinej.
Lexa!
Lexo!
Stop spying on Iva!
S tím šmírováním Ivy!
Good day, Marcelka.
Dobrý den, Marcelko.
A dignified afternoon, Tomas.
Důstojné odpoledne, Tomáši.
I think I've already apologized, haven't I?
Tak snad jsem se vám už omluvil, ne?
"I meant well" is not an apology.
Myslela jsem to dobře, není omluva.
Ivuska!
Ivuško!
I'm coming from the rental shop.
Jdu z půjčovny.
Oh, thank you.
Je, děkuju.
One moment.
Moment.
That's the whole costume?
To je celý kostým?
Those are two.
To jsou dva.
For Iva and for Sasa.
Pro Ivu i pro Sašu.
This thing can't cover anything at all.
Tady tohle to nemůže vůbec nic zakrýt.
God, it's like a two-piece swimsuit.
Ježiš, tady je to jako dvoudílný plavky.
You have a two-piece swimsuit?
Ty máš dvoudílný plavky?
Dad, please, can you stop embarrassing me in front of strangers?
Tati, prosím tě, můžeš mě přestat ztrapňovat před cizíma lidma?
Thank you.
Děkuju.
So I'm embarrassing you?
Tak já tě ztrapňuju?
And aren't you embarrassing yourself, little girl, wanting to writhe around in this nothing in front of some Arab guys?
A neztrapňuješ se holčičko náhodou sama, když v tomhletom nic chceš kroutit před nějakýma arabskýma chlapákama?
Tomas, now you're going too far.
Tomáši, to už přeháníte.
The Qatari prince is no brute.
Katarský princ není žádný chlapák.
A Qatari prince?
Katarský princ?
Yes, he confirmed attendance yesterday.
Ano, včera potvrdil účast.
It will be the social event of the year.
Bude to společenská událost roku.
Oh God.
Panebože.
You should be proud of Iva.
Měl byste na Ivu být pyšný.
Proud?
Pyšný?
When someone sees her in this, they'll drag her straight to a harem.
Až ji v tomhletom někdo uvidí, tak ji rovnou odtáhne do harému.
Tomas, this is a standard costume.
Tomáši, tohle je standardní kostým.
Last time it was rented by Livie Klausova and nobody dragged her anywhere.
Naposledy ho měla půjčenou Livie Klausová a tu taky nikdo nikam neodtáh.
Ivuska will look very lovely in it.
Ivuška v tom bude velice půvabná.
Fine, then let her show me in it.
Jo, tak ať se mi v tom ukáže.
What's the matter?
No co je?
If some prince gets to see it, why can't her own father?
Když to může vidět nějakej princ, proč by to nemohl vidět vlastní otec?
Go on.
Šup.
Tomas, calm down.
Tomáši, uklidněte se.
The Qatari prince is no slave driver.
Katarský princ není žádný otrokář.
Zoran says you won't find a kinder person among arms dealers.
Zoran říká, že laskavějšího člověka mezi obchodníky se zbraněmi nenajdete.
Marcelka, the Orient is a completely different world.
Marcelko, vždyť ten Orient je úplně jiný svět.
But it's changing, modernizing.
No ale mění se, modernizuje.
The prince's third wife, for example, has a driver's license completely legally.
Princova třetí manželka například má řidičský průkaz úplně legálně.
The prince arranged an exemption from the law.
Princ zařídil výjimku ze zákona.
Well, I did try to imagine it, but it was even worse.
Teda jsem si to představoval, ale bylo to jen horší.
Hey.
Čau.
You've got Milos?
Ty máš Miloše?
Yep.
No jo.
Wow.
Teda.
Some kids pulled him out of the basement, thought he was sick, and took him to the vet next door.
Nějaký děti ho vytáhli ze suterén, mysleli si, že je nemocný, tak ho odnesli vedle na veterinu.
Poor things.
Chudáci.
Oh well.
Ale co?
A few shots in the belly never killed anyone.
Pár injekcí do břicha ještě nikoho nezabilo.
Wow.
Teda.
Just like the old days.
Jako za starých časů.
You, me, and Milos.
Ty, já a Miloš.
Come, let's sit.
Pojď, posedíme.
Horvy really has it?
Ten Horvý ho fakt má?
Yeah.
No jo.
You can always count on Horvy.
Na Horvýho je vždycky spoleh.
When's he coming?
Kdy přijde?
Hard to say.
Těžko říct.
He called saying they threw him off the tram, so now he's riding it.
Volal, že ho vyhodili z tramvaje, takže teď jede na něm.
That's unbelievable.
To je neuvěřitelný.
I'm going to have a spitter.
Já budu mít fluskáka.
Well, if you hold out another month on the tenner.
No, když vydržíš ještě měsíc na desítce.
No problem.
Žádnej problém.
Hey.
Čau.
What are you doing?
Co blbneš?
Nothing, just stretching.
Nic, jenom jsem se protahoval.
Want something?
Dáš si něco?
Do you have coffee?
Máš už kafe?
Sure.
Jasně.
Doesn't it make you nervous though?
Ale ty z toho nejsi nervózní?
About what?
Z čeho?
That Sasa will be writhing in front of some Arab sheikh.
No, že se Saša bude kroutit před nějakým arabským šejkem.
Totally.
No jako pes.
What if he's got his eye on her.
Co když na ni bude mít zálusk.
Well yeah.
No to.
That prince, a chance like that might not come along again.
Ten princ, taková šance se už nemusí podruhý naskytnout.
It says here he's 60 and has 22 wives.
Tady píšou, že mu je 60 a že má 22 manželek.
See, that sounds perfect.
No teď říkám, že to nemá chybu.
The women are taken care of, they chat, and the men bother them once every two years.
O holky je postaráno, pokecaj si a chlapy otravují jednou za dva roky.
Well, it's against our culture.
Teď je to proti naší kultuře.
Does it say how much he makes?
Hele, píšou tam, kolik bere?
Yeah, but it's in camels.
Jo, ale je to ve velbloudech.
Wait, here.
Počkej, tady.
Average monthly income, 7,000 dromedaries.
Průměrnej měsíční příjem, 7000 dromedárů.
7,000?
7000?
I don't care about that.
Mě to nezajímá.
Why not?
Jak to?
I've realized a water heater is much better.
Pochopil jsem, že bojler je daleko lepší.
Even though I don't bathe.
I když se nemeju.
Pacovsky?
Pacovský?
Yeah, you're the water heater guy.
Jo, to jste vy přes ty bojlery.
Who's the water heater guy?
Kdo přes bojlery?
One moment.
Moment.
I ended up hiring a different company.
Nakonec jsem si najal jinou firmu.
Well, I'm already here.
No, tak už jsem tady.
Yeah, you're waiting in front of the building.
Jo, vy čekáte před barákem.
That soon, huh?
Tak brzo, ne?
Well, I'd better get down there.
No, tak já tam letím.
Thanks, great coffee.
Dík, bezva kafe.
It's the water.
To je tou vodou.
Lexa, listen to me carefully now.
Lexo, teď mě dobře poslouchej.
Come on, don't tell me we haven't met before.
No, to mi neříkejte, že se neznáme.
You remind me so much of someone.
Mě někoho strašně připomínáte.
I'd be very surprised.
To bych se teda divil.
This is my first time in this building, ausgerechnet, as we plumbers say.
V tomhle baráku jsem ausgerechnet poprvé, jak říkáme my instalatéři.
But what?
No ale co?
Damn.
Sakra.
What an idiot.
Blbý má.
And sorry again for locking you in the cellar.
Jo a ještě jednou se omlouvám za to, že vás zamkli ve sklepě.
Yeah, no problem.
Jo, to je v pohodě.
And is your bathroom worth the hassle now?
A je teď ta vaše koupelna za tu stávu.
The condensation pipe.
Kondenzní trubka.
That's a good one.
To je dobrý.
You really fell for it, huh?
Jste na to fakt skočil, jo?
Yeah, what an artist.
Jo, umělec.
What was your name again?
Jakže se to jmenujete, jste říkal?
Pacovsky.
Pacovský.
Right, Pacovsky, sure, sure.
Jo, Pacovský, jo, jasně, jasně.
I don't wanna get it wrong when I tell the guys at the shop.
Já bych to nepopletl, až to budu říkat chlapům na dílně.
Because they won't believe me anyway.
Neboť mi to stejně neuvěřej.
I guarantee it. Goodbye.
To vám garantuju, nashle.
Goodbye.
Nashle.
Dad.
Tati.
No.
Ne.
Do you realize how long we've been training?
Uvědomuješ si, jak dlouho jsme trénovaly?
You'll thank me one day.
Jednou mi poděkuješ.
Arab women will keep walking around in sacks because of you.
Arabský ženy kvůli tobě budou furt chodit v pytlích.
You too.
Ty taky.
Dad, Sasa won't go without me and Marcelka can't dance a herd of mares by herself.
Tati, Saša tam beze mě nepůjde a Marcelka sama stádo klisen neodtancuje.
She'll manage.
Ale to zvládne.
Marcelka, Iva, could you please talk to my father?
Marcelko, Ivo, mohla byste prosím vás promluvit s otcem?
Yeah, he won't let me go to the performance.
Jo, nechce mě pustit na vystoupení.
What do you mean, in the cellar?
Jak ve sklepě?
Who locked you in?
Kdo vás tam zavřel?
Your husband?
Manžel?
Ah, he saw you rehearsing in the costume.
Aha, viděl vás nacvičovat v kostýmu.
Exactly.
Ehnosko.
Ivuska, thank God, you're not in the cellar.
Ivuško, no zaplať Pán Bůh, nejsi ve sklepě.
That husband of Marcelka's must have Arab ancestors.
Ten Marcelčin manžel musí mít arabské předky.
He treats her like a slave.
No chová se k ní jako k otrokyni.
He's not the only one.
Není sám.
What?
Cože?
The grand vizier here put me under house arrest too.
No, tady velkej vezír mi taky dal zaracha.
Pacovsky, hello.
Pacovský, dobrý den.
It won't work without her.
Tady to nejde.
I can't dance a herd of mares alone.
Sama stádo klisen neodtancuju.
See?
Vidíš?
My daughter is no mare.
Moje dcera není žádná klisna.
Mr. Pacovsky, you don't understand.
Pane Pacovský, vy to nechápete.
Performing for the Qatari prince is an enormous honor.
Vystoupit před katarským princem, to je obrovská pocta.
If this goes well, it opens the door to all the Arab capitals.
Pokud se to podaří, tak máme otevřenou cestu do všech arabských metropolí.
I've been waiting my whole life for an opportunity like this.
Já celý život čekám na takovou příležitost.
Not a chance.
Ani na krok.
Goodbye, Cairo.
Sbohem, Káhiro.
Maybe you and Sasa could manage.
Třeba byste to se Sašou zvládly.
Who's Sasa?
Kdo je Saša?
The one with the chestnut in her belly button.
Ta s kaštenem v pupíku.
Goodbye, Cairo.
Sbohem, Káhiro.
Hey.
Nazdar.
Hi.
Ahoj.
I'm so sorry we have to part ways like this.
Je mi moc líto, že se musíme rozdělit takhle.
A tenner.
Desítka.
But it's my final offer.
Ale je to moje poslední slovo.
Who is that?
Kdo je to?
My brother.
Můj bratr.
Where did he learn the Bengali style?
Kde se naučil bengálský styl?
What, Ozzak?
Co, Ozzák?
Look, he's doing figure eights.
No hele, dělá osmičky.
That shoulder accent.
Ten akcent ramenem.
Excuse me, did you study under Fatima?
Promiňte, tančil jste u Fatimy?
No, under Simona.
Ne, u Simony.
That must be an excellent school.
To musí být skvělá škola.
Would you have two hours free?
Neměl byste dvě hodiny čas?
You could even meet the Qatari prince.
Mohl byste se třeba seznámit s katarským princem.
That's the one with the camels.
To je ten s těma velbloudama.
And he can be incredibly generous.
A dokáže být neuvěřitelně velkorysý.
He put his three favorite dromedaries up in the presidential suite at the Hilton.
Své tři nejoblíbenější dromedáry přiubytoval v prezidentském apartmá v Hiltonu.
Ozzak is a real man.
Ozzák je chlap.
He's got a great figure.
Má skvělou postavu.
Thanks.
Dík.
And once he's in the costume, nobody will notice.
No a až bude mít na sobě kostým, nikdo nic nepozná.
What about the mustache?
A co ten knír?
Have you ever seen the prince's third wife?
Viděl jste někdy princovu třetí manželku?
According to the driver of tram number 15, the trail of the llama stolen from the Prague Zoo ends at the Letenske namesti stop.
Podle svědectví řidiče tramvaje číslo 15 končí stopy lamy odcizené z pražské zoo na zastávce Letenské náměstí.
I originally thought it was just some big dog, but it didn't have a muzzle, so I let it off here.
Já jsem si teda původně myslel, že je to jenom nějakej velkej pes, ale neměl náhubek, tak jsem ho zde vysadil.
Nowhere.
Nikam.
I'll open it myself.
Otevřu sám.
Simona, you really went too far with that condensation pipe.
Teda Simono, s tou kondenzní trubkou jsi to fakt přehnala.
Stop being angry, we need to wash ourselves sometimes too.
Tak už se nečerti, my se taky musíme občas mejt.
Come on.
No tak.
Schnitzel?
Řízky?
Sasa just finished frying them.
Saša právě dosmažila.
Look, I'm using a bit of hot water.
Hele, čerpem trochu teplý vody.
It's the principle.
Jde jen o princip.
Great, so you don't mind if I take a shower?
Super, takže ti nebude vadit, když se už splachnu?
Horvat and I worked really hard.
My jsme se s Horvátem strašně nadřeli.
And he can stay out of my sight too.
Tak ten ať mi taky nechodí na oči.
Now all the plumbers in the neighborhood are laughing at me because of him.
Kvůli němu se mi teď smějí instalatéři v celý čtvrti.
Well, Horvy was always a real joker.
No to víš, Horvy, ten byl vždycky veselá kopa.
Is it good?
To je dobrý?
Exotic meat.
Exotický maso.
I've still got 50 kilos of it.
Mám ho ještě 50 kilo.
So can I?
Takže můžu?
Fine.
No jo.
Alright, go ahead, and don't use up all the water or I'll deal with you.
Tak šup a nevyčmejráte mi to všechno, jinak si vás podám.
Go!
Dělej!
Water fight!
Vodní bitva!
Yes, Mrs. Building Manager, you can count on me.
Ano, paní správcová, spolehněte se.
Yes, there won't be any more problems with my brother.
Ano, s mým bratrem už žádné problémy nebudou.
Right, yes, I'll keep an eye on him.
Tak, ano, dohlédnu na něj.
No, bear with me, but from next week it's over.
Ne, střeste mi ho, ale od týdne je konec.
I understand, certainly.
Já vám rozumím, jistě.
Well, then it couldn't have been him.
No, tak to nemohl být on.
Oh, then it probably was him.
Aha, tak to byl asi on.
No, no, of course I don't want to lose access to the common areas, or the cellar.
Ne, ne, samozřejmě, že nechci přijít o přístup do společných prostor, ani o sklep.
Yes, right, no, Mrs. Building Manager, you're kind, I know you let us off conditionally, I appreciate it.
Ano, tak, ne, paní správcová, jste hodná, já vím, že jste nám odpustila podmíněně, já si to vážím.
Mrs. Building Manager, I'll set my brother straight.
Paní správcová, já postavím bratra do latě.
He'll behave like clockwork.
Ten bude poslouchat jako hodinky.
I've had a very good influence on him lately.
Já v poslední době mám na něj velmi dobrý vliv.
Yes, a very good influence.
Ano, velmi dobrý vliv.
Yes, yes, of course no stomping on the stairs.
Ano, ano, samozřejmě žádné dupání po schodech.
Yes, no yelling.
Ano, žádné řvaní.
Yes, absolutely no spitting.
Ano, rozhodně žádné plivání.
No spitting, that I can swear to.
Žádné plivání, to vám můžu odpřísáhnout.
Yes, Mrs. Building Manager, thank you, goodbye, and I think everything will be just fine.
Ano, paní správcová, děkuji, nashledanou a myslím, že bude všechno v pořádku.